// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The path of the light is",
    answer: "Always a straight line",
    options: [
      "Always a straight line",
      "A curved line",
      "A zig-zag line",
      "Depends on the medium"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Uneven surfaces show................ reflection",
    answer: "irregular",
    options: [
      "irregular",
      "regular"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Incident ray, the reflected ray and .................. lie in the same plane",
    answer: "normal",
    options: [
      "normal",
      "different",
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "When we stand in front of our dressing table, our left hand seems to be right and right seems to be left. This is called",
    answer: "Lateral Inversion",
    options: [
      "Left-right confusion",
      "Lateral Inversion",
      "Up-side down phenomenon",
      "Mirage"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "An erect and enlarged image can be formed by",
    answer: "only a concave mirror",
    options: [
      "only a convex mirror",
      "only a concave mirror",
      "only a plane mirror",
      "both convex and concave mirror"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Beam of light striking the reflecting surface is called",
    answer: "Incident ray",
    options: [
      "Reflecting ray",
      "Incident ray",
      "Refracted ray",
      "Normal ray"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "In this retina of the eye, the area having no sensory cells is called",
    answer: "Blind Spot",
    options: [
      "iris",
      "Blind spot",
      "Cornea",
      "Dark Spot"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "In case of reflection of light the angle of incidence (i) and the angle of reflection (r) are related as",
    answer: "i = r",
    options: [
      "i = r",
      "i < r",
      "i > r",
      "No definite relation"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Visually impaired people can read and write using",
    answer: "braile system",
    options: [
      "electronic writer",
      "digital pens",
      "braile system",
      "hearing aids"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The defect due to which a person is not able to see the distant objects clearly",
    answer: "Myopia",
    options: [
      "Myopia",
      "Hypermetropia",
      "Cornea",
      "Cataract"
    ]
  },
];
